

Software Engineer/Business Development

Mobile: +65 91119248

E-Mail: sebastian.lzy@me.com

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastianlzy

**GitHub**: https://github.com/sebastianlzy **Website**: http://sebastianlzy.github.io/

Profile

A self-starter and quick learner.

Versatile skill set with experience in business development and software development. Experience in full stack development and mobile hybrid app development. Recognized skills in mentoring and mediating between employees, and in leading team projects.

Experience

Software Engineer, Afteryou Pte Ltd – May 14 - Present (SINGAPORE)

- 1. **Designed** and built a full suite mobile application, <u>Jarvis</u> targeting housing agents, which enabled them to save an average of 8 hours per week
- 2. **Implemented** continuous development tools that helped speed up 30% of development lifecycle
- 3. **Conceptualized** and enabled operations to streamline 50% of it's reporting process through Jarvis
- 4. **Designed** and build a full suite mobile application, <u>Winston</u> for service provider to enable them to diagnose, quote and accept jobs
- 5. **Constructed** and managed company's website, online order form and online inventory listing which improved stickiness of housing agents to our company
- 6. **Provided** technical support to assist in marketing and publicity effort that resulted in better customer experience
- 7. **Integrated** with external API services to help streamline complicated processes (e.g. integration with Xero for financial services, integration with mandrill for mailing services)

System Analyst, CSIT – July 2013 - May 2014 (SINGAPORE)

- 1. **Designed** and implemented web service architecture on existing applications to allow interoperability and improve security
- 2. **Led** the development of a web application that focuses on displaying and consolidating vital information for analysis
- 3. **Setup** offline common repositories (Git and Maven) to improve and foster better collaboration between developers

Software Engineer (Internship), Rocketfuel Inc - Jan 2011- Dec 2011 (USA)

1. **Conceptualized** and developed user friendly features based on business requirements to increase employees' productivity by 30%

- 2. **Collaborated** with end-users to design and improve overall system usability, which resulted in an average of 3 fewer clicks per transaction
- 3. **Spearheaded** and delivered a revenue forecasting feature with a 95% reliability to enhance visibility of the company's financial position

Student Marketer, Playmoolah - April 2011-June 2011(USA)

- 1. **Convinced** and influenced the establishment of product features based on detailed analysis of information collected over a period of 3 months
- 2. **Coordinated** marketing strategy across 4 different social media platforms to generate greater public awareness of the product

Portfolio

## Jarvis



https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=afteryou.Jarvishttps://itunes.apple.com/us/app/jarvis/id904514072?ls=1&mt=8



#### Winston

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.afteryou.Winston

Afteryou Website http://afteryou.co/#/

#### Education

National University of Singapore (NUS), Bachelor of Computing (Major in Information System, Minor in Technopreneurship, Minor in Specialization in Service Science Management and Engineering) - 4 years

1. Cap 4.11/5, 2nd Upper Class Honors

Stanford University, NUS Oversea Colleges - 1 year

- 1. Gained insights through networking sessions with entrepreneurs and business leaders
- 2. **Notable subjects taken:** New Venture Creation, Global Entrepreneurial Marketing and Start-up business case

Singapore Polytechnic, Diploma in Information Communication Technology - 3 years

1. **GPA** 3.83/4 (Top 10 percentile - Diploma with merit)

### Skills

### **Advance**

Javascript - (AngularJS, Ionic framework, HapiJS, Node, Jquery, Skel) Intermediate

Ruby on Rails, Java (Spring Core, Spring MVC), Python, Cordova

## **Databases**

MySQL, Postgres

# **Tool Usage**

Bower, Yeoman, Grunt, Git, Gulp, Maven, Hibernate

# Scholastic Achievement CareersGo Programming Challenge (Champion Team) - Dec 2012

- 1. Led a team of 6 with various skills sets to win a 13 week competition
- 2. Planned and designed the structure of both the web and mobile career portal mySAP ERP TERP 10 Certificate - Dec 2010

The Institution of Engineering & Technology Prize, Singapore Polytechnic - Dec 2010 Director Honor List for academic year, Singapore Polytechnic - July 2005, 06 & 07 CISCO system book prize (Merit Award) - July 2005